Inventory of the Woolfolk Family Papers 1775-1893
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of various persons, A-Z, 1775-1860. (Box-folder 4:10-10:28)
  - Woolfolk (John George): Invoices, bonds and drafts of John G. Woolfolk and John Hoomes, 1800-1810. (Box-folder 6:18)
    See also John Hoomes estate.
  - Woolfolk (John William), 1843., 240 pp. (Box-folder 7:19)
    Student's notebook, containing notes on physiology and on the Bible. See Manuscript Volumes, Students' Notebooks.
  - Woolfolk, John William, 1840-1892. (Box-folder 7:19)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Allen (Wilson) to Jourdan Woolfolk, trustee for Sophia Allen, n.d. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): 1822., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Trust deed covering a tract of land.
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Chevis (He T.) vs. William G. Maury and Jourdan Woolfolk., 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Suit.
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Farish (Hazelwood) to John Hoomes and Jourdan Woolfolk, trustees for Thomas B. Farish and Wilson Allen, 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Trust deed covering stages, horses and mail contracts from Fredericksburg to Stafford Court House and to Halifax Court House, and a tract of land in Caroline County.
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Hudgin (Robert) to Walter G. Hudgin, 1865., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Assignment of a debt to secure his creditors.
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Kent (Horace L.) vs. Jourdan Woolfolk, security for W. Curtiss, 1837., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): Pendleton (John L.) to Hiram Childs and Jourdan Woolfolk, trustees for Williamson Talley, 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Trust deed covering a tract of land in Caroline County called Edmundsberry, and the fees due him as clerk of Caroline County and Superior Court.
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan) vs. Thomas Priddy et als., creditors of Wilson Allen, 1821-1824., 4 items. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan), assignee of Alexander Chapman, vs. Nelson Beazely, 1826., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan): vs. Philip Chapman. 1837., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan), 1838., 3 items. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Agreements for the sale of mulberry trees.
  - William H. Tennent for Woolfolk (Jourdan) vs. Samuel C. Thornton and William Pare, 1840., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan) vs. James H. Garnett and Joseph C. Spindle. 1858., 1 item. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Suit in Caroline County, Virginia.
  - Agreements for lease of certain of (Jourdan) Woolfolk lands in Caroline County, 1867-1869., 3 items. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan), agreements with farm laborers, 1868., 2 items. (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Jourdan Woolfolk in account with Wortham and Magruder, commission merchants, Richmond, Virginia, 1820-1848., 61 items. (Box-folder 7:21)
    Accounts and letters. See also bound volumes.
  - Woolfolk Jourdan estate account and vouchers, 1809-1872., 1,258 items. (Box-folder 8:22-9:27)
  - Woolfolk (Jourdan II) accounts and invoices, 1867-1893. (Box-folder 10:28)
  - Woolfolk (Pichegru), estimate of income and expenses for the plantation at Harris', n.d., 1 item.
  - Woolfolk (Samuel) estate, bond, 1816., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:28)
    John C. Woolfolk and others to Frances Woolfolk, administratrix of Charles Woolfolk who was executor of Samuel Woolfolk. Refunding bond for the settlement of the estate.
  - Woolfolk (Samuel): Notes and receipts, 1810-1816. (Box-folder 10:28)
  - Timothy Chandler and Jourdan Woolfolk, trustees for Wortham (Elliott), 1830-1831., 3 items. (Box-folder 10:28)
  Series 6: Other papers
- Other papers, 1810-1871. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Vaccination information, 1829, 1937., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:29)
    List of slaves vaccinated (1829), and list of members of the Woolfolk family and slaves vaccinated, (1837).
  - Formula for shoe blacking, 1830., 1 item. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Other papers, 1819-1871., 8 items. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Unidentified invoices and memoranda, 1810-1846., 28 items. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Fragments, n.d., 13 items. (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Wrappings and envelopes, n.d., 86 items. (Box-folder 10:29)
  Series 7: Bound volumes
- Bound volumes, 1788-1880. (Box 11-12)
  - Ledger of John C. Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1788-1893., 1 volume; 120 pp., 12 1/2 x 9 inches. (Box 11)
  - Account book of John C. Woolfolk, 1793-1846., 1 volume; 150 pp., 13 1/4 x 8 1/4 inches. (Box 12)
    The volume also contains stage line accounts, 1794-1796.
  - The estate of John G. Woolfolk in account with Jourdan Woolfolk, Hawes Coleman and John N. Burke, administrators, 1819-1821., 1 volume; 34 pp. 13 1/2 x 8 1/4 inches. (Box 11)
  - Accounts of the stage line for transportation of passengers, 1812-1813., 1 volume; 150 pp., 16 x 6 3/4 inches. (Box 12)
    The volume also contains blacksmith and grain accounts of Elizabeth P. Woolfolk, 1823-1825, and accounts of the estate of Elizabeth P. Woolfolk, 1839.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1814-1815., 1 volume; 48 pp., 6 1/4 x 4 inches. (Box 12)
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1818-1819., 1 volume; 64 pp., 6 1/2 x 4 inches.. (Box 11)
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1818-1819., 1 volume; 132 pp., 7 1/4 x 7 inches. (Box 12)
    The volume also contains personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Account book of Jourdan Woolfolk, 1819-1883., 1 volume; 350 pp., 12 1/2 x 8 1/4 inches. (Box 11)
    This volume contains accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk as administrator, trustee and guardian, and accounts with the stage line.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1821-1825., 1 volume; 204 pp., 6 1/2 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 11)
    The book contains also accounts of the estate of John C. Woolfolk and personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1825-1826., 1 volume; 80 pages. 7 1/4 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 12)
    The book contains also accounts of the estate of John C. Woolfolk with Jourdan Woolfolk and personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1826., 1 volume; 30 pp., 6 3/4 x 4 inches. (Box 12)
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1826-1827., 1 volume; 104 pp. and 2 loose sheets, 6 3/4 x 4 1/2 inches. (Box 12)
    The book contains also accounts of the estate of John G. Woolfolk with Jourdan Woolfolk and personal accounts John C. Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1827-1829., 1 volume; 163 pp., 61/2 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 12)
    The book contains also a few personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1829-1831., 1 volume; 146 pp., 6 1/4 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 11)
    The book contains also personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk, containing accounts of the stage line, 1831-1834., 1 volume; 106 pp. and 9 loose sheets, 6 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 12)
    The book contains also many personal accounts of Jourdan Woolfolk.
  - Memorandum book of Jourdan Woolfolk containing accounts of the stage line, 1832-1837., 1 volume; 160 pp., and 2 loose sheets, 6 1/2 x 4 1/4 inches. (Box 12)
  - Account book of Jourdan and John W. Woolfolk, 1827-1865., 1 volume; 156 pages. l5 1/2 x 6 1/2 inches. (Box 12)
    The book contains also stage line accounts, 1827-1833, and post office department drafts received by J. W. Woolfolk & Co. for carrying mail, 1836-1847.
  - Account book of Jourdan and John W. Woolfolk, 1847-1880., 1 volume; 136 pp., 13 1/4 x 8 1/4 inches. (Box 11)
  - Account book of John W. Woolfolk, 1839-1869., 1 volume; 332 pages. 12 1/4 x 8 inches. (Box 12)
  Series 8: Papers relating to the stage and mail service operated by members of the Woolfolk family
- Papers relating to the stage and mail service operated by members of the Woolfolk family, 1789-1845. (Box-folder 13:30-14:40)
  Papers in this series have not been arranged yet.
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1789, 1802-1836. (Box-folder 13:30)
    Contains tax records, receipts, correspondence, and accounts.
  - Contracts and miscellaneous financial records, 1815-1845. (Box-folder 13:31)
    Contains a contract with the U.S. Government and several Post Office contracts, a share in the Potomac Steamboat Company, correspondence and miscellaneous financial records.
  - Miscellaneous financial and legal records, 1798-1844. (Box-folder 13:32)
    Contains receipts, accounts, records and correspondence pertaining to legal questions regarding the Woolfolk family business.
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1817-1824. (Box-folder 13:33)
    Contains receipts and accounts.
  - Accounts, 1809-1836. (Box-folder 13:34)
  - Correspondence, 1836-1838. (Box-folder 13:35)
  - Government publications, ca. 1833-1834, 1841, 1849, 2 volumes (incomplete) and 2 items. (Box-folder 14:36)
    Includes two issues of the National Intelligenzer, 1841 and 1849, as well as two incomplete volumes of government publications on legislation regarding mail service (ca. 1833-1834).
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1796-1821. (Box-folder 14:37-38)
    Includes accounts, business correspondence and tax receipts for John G. Woolflok, John Hoomes, and Woolfolk & Holmes with various clients.
  - Business correspondence received by Jourdan Woolfolk, 1813, 1828, 1836-1838. (Box-folder 14:39-40)
    Includes letters received by Jourdan Woolfolk, Bowling Green, Caroline County, Virginia. The bulk of the letters were written by B.[?] Bradley, Washington D.C. Also includes letters from Conway Robinson, President of the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad Company, and letters (copied) by Bradley to Robinson and others.
  Series 9: Papers relating to members of the Woolfolk Family, A-Z
- Papers relating to members of the Woolfolk Family, A-Z, 1794-1890. (Box-folder 15:41-18:58 and 20:65-69)
  - Papers relating Elizabeth P. Woolfolk, 1815-1839. (Box-folder 15:41)
    Includes accounts and receipts for household items and relating to agricultural operations, including a medical bill for slaves, tuition bills, and receipts for wages paid to James Cox.
  - Papers relating to John Woolfolk, 1834-1854. (Box-folder 15:42)
    Includes accounts and receipts of John Woolfolk, including a subscription list for a church building (n.d.), as well as a list of bonds on his estate (1854).
  - Papers relating to Frances Woolfolk and his estate, 1794-1801. (Box-folder 15:43)
    Includes will of Frances Woolfolk (1794), estate inventory and papers relating to his estate and his two orphaned children, Sallie and Anna (John G. Woolfolk, guardian). Also includes medical bills with medical fees for visits to slaves, as well as tuition bills.
  - Papers relating to John Woolfolk, 1839-1857., Several bonds are mutilated: signature has been torn out. (Box-folder 15:44)
    Includes bonds, bills, accounts, and receipts.
  - Papers relating to John Woolfolk, 1786, 1810-1845. (Box-folder 16:45)
    Includes accounts, receipts, legal records, a workmen's book, and a surveyer's report.
  - Papers relating to John G. Woolfolk's estate, 1805-1852. (Box-folder 16:46-49 and 17:50-52)
    Includes accounts, bonds, an indemnification bond, insurance policies, receipts, memoranda, banknotes, deeds and indentures, as well as a deed of trust documenting the sale of a slave and her two children. Also included are accounts of Sophia Hoomes with John G. Woolfolk, who was her guardian. Also includes a letter from Richard Woolfolk, Jefferson County, 1810, explaining his financial problems and the sale of slaves. He also mentions the sale of a horse to St. George Tucker.
  - Papers relating to the Estate of John W. Woolfolk, 1843-1890. (Box-folder 17:53-54)
    Includes correspondence, report cards from Bethany College (West Virginia), accounts, receipts, and bills.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk correspondence, 1821-1866. (Box-folder 18:55-56)
    Includes correspondence dating 1821-1866. Of special interest is the Civil War correspondence. A letter to Jourdan Woolfolk, written by Roy Huly [?], Edge Mont. [?], dated 26 July 1864, describes an encouter with Sheridan's forces: according to Huly's account, horses and four slave boys were led away and but there was little damage property. Also includes a group of letters from Confederate soldiers, a group of letters relating to the culture of silkworms, and bancruptcy notices.
  - Papers relating to Jourdan Woofolk, 1833-1867. (Box-folder 18:57)
    Included are indentures, agreements, court summons, membership certificates, insurance policies, and estate accounts for John M. Burke.
  - Jourdan Woolfolk account book, 1854-1868., 1 volume. (Box-folder 18:58)
    Accounts with various individuals. Includes name index.
  - Papers relating to Jourdan Woolfolk, 1815-1823. (Box-folder 20:65-68)
    Vouchers.
  - Papers relating to Sarah Woolfolk, 1807-1813., 1 item. (Box-folder 20:69)
    Bond.
  Series 10: Papers relating to the Estate of John Hoomes
- Papers relating to the Estate of John Hoomes, 1796-1817. (Box-folder 19:59.)
  - Papers relating to the Estate of John Hoomes, 1796-1817. (Box-folder 19:59)
    Includes financial and legal records relating to the estate of John Hoomes, among those an abstract of his will.
  Series 11: Papers relating to Antioch Reformed Church, Bowling Green, Virginia
- Papers relating to Antioch Reformed Church, Bowling Green, Virginia, 1853-1859. (Box-folder 19:60.)
  - Papers relating to Antioch Reformed Church, Bowling Green, Virginia, 1853-1859. (Box-folder 19:60)
    Subscription lists, invoices and receipts relative to the erection of Antioch Christian Church, Bowling Green, Virginia.
  Series 12: Records relating to the Caroline County troops of cavalry
- Records relating to the Caroline County troops of cavalry, 1816-1820. (Box-folder 19:61.)
  - Records relating to the Caroline County troops of cavalry, 1816-1820. (Box-folder 19:61)
    Includes lists of delinquents at muster 1816-1817, amount of money collected at a muster, n.d., reports of troop meetings, and a financial record.
  Series 13: Newspapers
- Newspapers, 1842. (Box-folder 19:64.)
  - Newspaper, 1842., 1 issue. (Box-folder 19:64)
    Issue of the Richmond Enquirer, September 6, 1842. The following issues of the Richmond Whig and Public Advertiser that were originally part of this collection, were moved to the Newspaper Collection: February 15, 1839, October 7, 1840, and February 12, 1842.
  Series 14: Miscellaneous
- Miscellaneous, 1796- ca.193-. (Box-folder 19:62-63.)
  - Miscellaneous, 1796- ca.193-. (Box-folder 19:62-63)
    Includes memoranda, receipts, instructions, accountbooks, bonds. A plat showing property lines and listing the names of owners, n.d. A 1795 copy of Constitutions, Rules and Regulations of the Mutual Assurance Society of Virginia was transferred to the Rare Books Collection.